First, we'll talk about the goal of the diffusion model,
首先，我们将讨论扩散模型的目标，
and then we'll talk about training the models themselves on this data.
最后我们会讨论如何在这些数据上训练模型。
What is the goal of diffusion models?
那么，扩散模型的目标是什么呢？
Well, you have a lot of training data,
好吧，你有很多的训练数据，
such as these sprite images that you see down here of video game characters.
比如你在这里看到的视频游戏角色的图像。
So now, how do we make these images useful to the neural network?
那么现在，我们如何
让这些图像对神经网络有用呢？
And that could be finer details, such as, you know, the hair color of the sprite or that it's wearing a buckle for its belt.
这可能是更细微的细节，比如，
你知道，游戏角色的头发颜色或者它的腰带扣。
But it also could be general outlines, like of its head and body, and everything in between that.
也可能是大概的轮廓，
像头和身体的轮廓，以及所有在这之间的东西。
And one way to do that, one way to kind of take your data and be able to emphasize either finer details
有一种方法可以做到这一点，
就是用你的数据强调细节或者大概轮廓。
or general outlines is actually to add different levels of noise.
实际上，这就是在不同程度上添加噪声。
And it's known as a noising process.
这被称为噪声过程。
You can imagine an ink drop into a glass of water.
你可以想象一滴墨水滴入一杯水中。
and as you add noise, it will disappear until you have no idea which sprite it actually was.
当你添加噪声时，它会消失，
直到你不知道它究竟是哪个游戏角色。
Well, when it's Bob the sprite, you want the neural network to say,
嗯，当它是角色Bob的时候，
你希望神经网络能说，
"Yeah, that's Bob the sprite, to keep Bob as is.
“对，这就是角色Bob！
保持Bob的原样，
If it's probably Bob, if it's likely to be Bob,
如果它可能是Bob，
如果它很可能是Bob，
then you probably want the neural network to say, you know,
那么你可能希望神经网络能说：
"There's some noise on here.
“这上面有一些噪声。
And if it's just an outline of a sprite now,
如果它现在只是一个角色的轮廓，
here you can only get a sense that this is probably a sprite person,
你只能感觉到这可能是一个角色人物，
but it could be Bob or Fred or maybe even Nancy,
但它可能是Bob，
或者Fred，甚至可能是Nancy，
And finally, if you have no idea, if it looks like absolutely nothing,
最后，如果你一点也不清楚，
如果它看起来完全不像什么，
you still want it to look more like a sprite.
你还是希望它更像一个游戏角色。
All right, so let's take a look at what that noising process,
好了，那么让我们看看这个添加噪声的过程，
that process of adding noise progressively, looks like over time.
随着时间的推移，
逐渐添加噪声的过程是什么样子的。
And there it goes, an ink drop that's fully diffused in a glass of water.
然后它就消失了，
一滴墨水在一杯水里完全扩散开来。
So now on to training that neural network.
那么现在让我们
开始训练那个神经网络吧。
So it learns to take different noisy images and turn them back into sprites.
它学会将不同的噪声图像变回游戏角色。
That is your goal.
这就是你的目标。
starting with the no idea level, where it is just pure noise,
从完全没有主意的级别开始，
那里只有纯粹的噪声，
to starting to give a semblance of maybe there's a person in there,
开始让人感觉可能有一个人在里面，
to looking like Fred, and then finally a sprite that looks like Fred.
看起来像Fred，
然后最后是一个看起来像Fred的游戏角色。
And I just want to call out that the no idea level of noise is really important because it is normally distributed.
我想强调的是，没有主意的噪声级别
非常重要，因为它是正态分布的。
And what I mean by that is each of those pixels is sampled from a normal distribution,
我的意思是，每一个像素
都是从一个正态分布中抽样的，
also known as a Gaussian distribution or a bell-shaped curve.
也被称为高斯分布或者钟形曲线。
So when you want to ask the neural network for a new sprite, such as Fred here,
所以当你想要让神经网络
给你一个新的角色，比如这里的Fred，
you can sample noise from that normal distribution,
你可以从那个正态分布中抽样噪声，
and then you can get a completely new sprite by using the neural network to just remove that noise progressively.
然后你可以通过让神经网络
逐渐移除那个噪声来得到一个全新的游戏角色。
So now you've reached your goal.
所以现在你达到了你的目标：
You can get even more sprites beyond all those that you had trained on.
得到更多的、你没有训练过的游戏角色。
In the next video, we'll cover sampling.
在下一个视频中，我们将介绍抽样。